Guide to the Kathy Dobkin Papers TAM.852
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Kathy Dobkin Papers
1952-2018
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Dobkin, Kathy
Katherine Dobkin Living Trust
TAM.852
4.54 Linear Feet in 9 manuscript boxes, 1 media box, and 22 audiocassettes in shared housing
58 audiocassettes
543.8 Megabytes in 3 recordings
Kathy Dobkin was a broadcaster at WNET (Channel 13) and WBAI from the 1970s to the early 2000s. In September 1970, Dobkin led a station-wide effort to produce an on-air reading of Leo Tolstoy's War and Peace, unabridged and with a Soviet musical score. The production, which lasted five straight days for 24 hours a day, was at that point was the longest continuous on-air broadcast in radio history. The Kathy Dobkin Papers (dated 1952-2018) consists of materials created and collected by Dobkin documenting her work at WBAI, with particular emphasis on the station's on-air broadcast of War and Peace. Materials include ephemera, production files, research materials, and press clippings, as well as audio recordings of the broadcast. The collection also includes a smaller amount of personal correspondence and materials on the history of WBAI. In addition to documenting this particular project, the materials in this collection also reflect Soviet arts and culture, particularly through the lens of the Cold War, through Dobkin's research materials.
Scope and Contents
The Kathy Dobkin Papers (dated 1952-2018) consists of materials created and collected by Dobkin documenting her work at WBAI, with particular emphasis on the station's on-air broadcast of War and Peace. Materials include ephemera, production files, research materials, and press clippings, as well as audio recordings of the broadcast. The collection also includes a smaller amount of personal correspondence and materials on the history of WBAI. In addition to documenting this particular project, the materials in this collection also reflect Soviet arts and culture, particularly through the lens of the Cold War, through Dobkin's research materials.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Appraisal
During acquisition, the following items were appraised out of the collection by the curator: duplicate promotional materials for the War and Peace marathon reading (including duplicative posters and postcards); Dobkin's childhood report cards and diplomas; off-air recordings of Democracy Now! episodes; and optical discs duplicating the physical collection or held by the Pacifica Radio Archives.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the Katherin Dobkin Living Trust in May 2025; the accession number associated with this gift is 2025.055.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted. An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.
Biographical / Historical
Kathy Dobkin was a broadcaster at WNET (Channel 13) and WBAI from the 1970s to the early 2000s. In September 1970, Dobkin led a station-wide effort to produce an on-air reading of Leo Tolstoy's War and Peace, unabridged and with a Soviet musical score. The production, which lasted five straight days for 24 hours a day, was at that point was the longest continuous on-air broadcast in radio history.
Related Materials
WBAI recordings of the War and Peace broadcast, as well as commemorations of the event, were held by the Pacifica Radio Archives until 2024, after which they have been transferred to the American Archive of Public Broadcasting.
Russian literature; Music -- Russia; Composers -- Russia; Radio broadcasters; Cold War.; Katherine Dobkin Living Trust; WBAI Radio (New York, N.Y.)
- Education, 1959-1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- New Lincoln, 1960-2005 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Pare Laurentz, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Channel 13, 1981-2012 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Clippings, Notes, Ephemera, 1985-1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Arlene Shostack, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- DACS Pack, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- DACS Pack, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- DACS Pack, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence -- Personal, 1964-2013 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Career, 1962-1998 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Leonard (WBAI Station Cat), 1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Aesthetics/Philosophy, 1964-1981 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Literature (Not Russian), 1983-1993 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Original Writings (Not Russian), 1958-1965 (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
- Music Programs (Not Russian), 1974 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Music -- A-E (Not Russian), 1969-2010 (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
- Music -- F-J (Not Russian), 1981-2018 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Music -- K-O (Not Russian), 1971-2006 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Music -- P-T (Not Russian), 1973-2007 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Music -- U-Z (Not Russian), 1970-1983 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Music -- General (Not Russian), 1964-1995 (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
- Russian Composers -- A-M, 1985-2003 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Russian Composers -- N-Z, 1977-2003 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Russian Music, 1961-2005 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Borodin, Alexander, 1965-1994 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Glinka, Mikhail, 1977-1984 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Khachaturian, Aram, 1978-2003 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Mussorgsky, Modest, 1954-2005 (Box 3, Folder 10-12, Box 4, Folder 1)
- Prokofiev, Sergei, 1977-2007 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1973-1992 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Rimsky-Korsakov, Nikolai, 1966-2003 (Box 4, Folder 4-6)
- Scriabin, Alexander, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Shaporin, Yuri, 1972-2005 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Shostakovich, Dmitri, 1975-2006 (Box 4, Folder 9-12)
- Stravinsky, Igor, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Tchaikovsky, Pyotr Ilyich, 1959-1998 (Box 5, Folder 2-5)
- Christoff, Boris, 1980-1993 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Russian Opera Singers, 1993-1995, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Bolshoi Opera, 1975-1991 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Russian Ballet/Dance, 1975, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
- WBAI History, 1960-1974 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- War and Peace -- General, 1970-1987 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- War and Peace -- 35th Anniversary, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 12-14)
- War and Peace -- Broadcast Interviews, 1970; TW_TAM_852_ER_1
- War and Peace -- Excerpts, 1971; TW_TAM_852_ER_2
- War and Peace -- Museum of Broadcasting, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
- War and Peace -- Fan Mail, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 3-5)
- War and Peace -- Press, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 6-7)
- War and Peace -- Press Releases, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- War and Peace -- Facts, Figures, Tape Timings, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- War and Peace -- Celebrity List, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 10-11)
- War and Peace -- Photographs, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- War and Peace -- Personal Correspondence, 1970-2005 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- War and Peace -- Promos for KPFA Broadcast, 1971; TW_TAM_852_ER_3
- War and Peace -- Rebroadcast Nightly, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
- War and Peace -- At Other Stations, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- War and Peace -- "The Packet", 1971 (Box 7, Folder 4-5)
- War and Peace -- Soviet Film, 1968-1994 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- War and Peace -- Buttons, Postcards, Posters, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 7, Box Shared Tamiment 203, Folder 1)
- War and Peace -- Press and Ephemera, 1978-2007 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- WBAI Program, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Chekov, Anton, 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Dostoevsky, Fyodor, 1957-1972 (Box 7, Folder 11-12)
- Gogol, Nikolai, 1973-1977 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Nabokov, Vladimir, 1973-1981 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Other Russian Writers, 1971-1983 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Pushkin, Alexander, 1964-1999 (Box 8, Folder 4-5)
- Shakespeare and Russian Literature, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Tolstoy, Leo, 1968-1994 (Box 8, Folder 7-8)
- Turgenev, Ivan, 1977-1988 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Soviet Literary Criticism, 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Russian Literature -- General, 1970-2005 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Dobkin Papers on Russian Liteature, 1960-1965 (Box 8, Folder 12-13)
- "Long Russian Winter" Schedules, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Fan Mail to Russian Programs (Not War and Peace), 1969-1984 (Box 9, Folder 2-3)
- Russia -- General, 1964-1998 (Box 9, Folder 4-7)
- Russia -- Currency, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Russia -- Correspondence, 1970-1976 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Russia -- Film, 1983-1985 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- War and Peace -- WBAI Broadcast, 1970; cuid44352
  - Tape 1-3, cuid44353 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44353)
  - Tape 4-6, cuid44354 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44354)
  - Tape 7-9, cuid44355 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44355)
  - Tape 10-12, cuid44356 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44356)
  - Tape 13-15, cuid44357 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44357)
  - Tape 16-18, cuid44358 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44358)
  - Tape 19-21, cuid44359 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44359)
  - Tape 22-24, cuid44360 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44360)
  - Tape 25-27, cuid44361 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44361)
  - Tape 28-30, cuid44362 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44362)
  - Tape 31-33, cuid44363 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44363)
  - Tape 34, cuid44364 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44364)
  - Tape 35-37, cuid44365 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44365)
  - Tape 38-40, cuid44366 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44366)
  - Tape 41-43, cuid44367 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44367)
  - Tape 44-46, cuid44368 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44368)
  - Tape 47-49, cuid44369 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44369)
  - Tape 50-52, cuid44370 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44370)
  - Tape 53-54, cuid44371 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44371)
  - Tape 55-56, cuid44372 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44372)
  - Tape 55-58, cuid44373 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44373)
  - Tape 57-59, cuid44374 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44374)
  - Tape 59-62, cuid44375 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44375)
  - Tape 60-62, cuid44376 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44376)
  - Tape 63-65, cuid44377 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44377)
  - Tape 66-69, cuid44378 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44378)
  - Tape 70-72, cuid44379 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44379)
  - Tape 73-74, cuid44380 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44380)
  - Tape 75-78, cuid44381 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44381)
  - Tape 79-82, cuid44382 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44382)
  - Tape 83-86, cuid44383 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44383)
  - Tape 87-89, cuid44384 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44384)
  - Tape 90-93, cuid44385 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44385)
  - Tape 94-97, cuid44386 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44386)
  - Tape 98-102, cuid44387 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44387)
  - Tape 103-107, cuid44388 (Box 10, Audiocassette cuid44388)
  - Tape 108-111, cuid44389 (Box Shared Tamiment 195, Audiocassette cuid44389)
  - Tape 112-115, cuid44390 (Box Shared Tamiment 195, Audiocassette cuid44390)
  - Tape 116-119, cuid44391 (Box Shared Tamiment 195, Audiocassette cuid44391)
  - Tape 120-123, cuid44392 (Box Shared Tamiment 195, Audiocassette cuid44392)
  - Tape 124-127, cuid44393 (Box Shared Tamiment 195, Audiocassette cuid44393)
  - Tape 128-132, cuid44394 (Box Shared Tamiment 195, Audiocassette cuid44394)
  - Tape 134-135, cuid44395 (Box Shared Tamiment 195, Audiocassette cuid44395)
  - Tape 136-138, cuid44396 (Box Shared Tamiment 195, Audiocassette cuid44396)
  - Tape 139-141, cuid44397 (Box Shared Tamiment 195, Audiocassette cuid44397)
  - Tape 142-144, cuid44398 (Box Shared Tamiment 195, Audiocassette cuid44398)
  - Tape 145-146, cuid44399 (Box Shared Tamiment 202, Audiocassette cuid44399)
  - Tape 147-148, cuid44400 (Box Shared Tamiment 202, Audiocassette cuid44400)
  - Tape 149-151, cuid44401 (Box Shared Tamiment 202, Audiocassette cuid44401)
  - Tape 152-153, cuid44402 (Box Shared Tamiment 202, Audiocassette cuid44402)
  - Tape 154-157, cuid44403 (Box Shared Tamiment 202, Audiocassette cuid44403)
  - Tape 159-160, cuid44404 (Box Shared Tamiment 202, Audiocassette cuid44404)
  - Tape 161-162, cuid44405 (Box Shared Tamiment 202, Audiocassette cuid44405)
  - Tape 163-164, cuid44406 (Box Shared Tamiment 202, Audiocassette cuid44406)
  - Tape 165-166, cuid44407 (Box Shared Tamiment 202, Audiocassette cuid44407)
  - Tape 167-169, cuid44408 (Box Shared Tamiment 202, Audiocassette cuid44408)
  - Excerpts, cuid44409 (Box Shared Tamiment 202, Audiocassette cuid44409)
- Cassette from Answering Machine -- Side 1: Jesse Message; Side 2: Silky Meowing; Steve Post Messages; "Steve Post on BAI Telling of Incident Where I Touched Richard Nixon", 1976-1980; cuid44410 (Box Shared Tamiment 195, Audiocassette cuid44410)